<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>installation on genneko</title>
    <link>https://genneko.github.io/tags/installation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in installation on genneko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2017 - 2020 genneko</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 20:26:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://genneko.github.io/tags/installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Joplin desktop app on FreeBSD</title>
      <link>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/application/howto-use-joplin-on-freebsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 20:26:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/application/howto-use-joplin-on-freebsd/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick note on how I build and use the latest Joplin desktop app on FreeBSD.
For my initial exploration of Joplin on FreeBSD, please refer to the previous post.
Target Version The current target version of this article is Joplin Electron (pre-)release v1.0.177 (Dec 2019). Building Joplin I take the following steps to build Joplin desktop on my FreeBSD 12.1-RELEASE system (with XFCE4 desktop).
 Install dependencies such as Electron and Nodejs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ThinkPad T480 is my new main laptop which runs FreeBSD</title>
      <link>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/hardware/freebsd-on-thinkpad-t480/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:50:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/hardware/freebsd-on-thinkpad-t480/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been using FreeBSD as my primary server OS for quite a long time.
But, for unknown reasons, I have never seriously used it on client workstations.
Maybe it&#39;s partly because I&#39;m a CUI-oriented person who loves doing things on text terminals as much as possible.
Actually, I have been pretty happy with any client OS as long as I could use a decent terminal on it, so that I could SSH into FreeBSD servers where I spent a lot of time doing jobs which didn&#39;t require graphical interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Joplin (Terminal and Desktop) and Web Clipper on FreeBSD</title>
      <link>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/application/joplin-on-freebsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 23:20:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/application/joplin-on-freebsd/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR (2020-01-15)
This article describes my initial exploration of Joplin in June 2019. It&#39;s not intended to be a tutorial/howto and it&#39;s not necessarily up to date.
Please refer to the newer post for more up-to-date and concise description on how to use Joplin on FreeBSD.
I&#39;ve been using Evernote since April 2011.
Although there were times the app got disappointing updates or the service was unexpectedly interrupted (or more often expectedly interrupted by regular maintenance), it had been a great app/service and hopefully it is and it will be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using FreeBSD&#39;s Bootonly Installer Behind a Proxy</title>
      <link>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/system/bootonly-install-behind-proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 21:58:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/system/bootonly-install-behind-proxy/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been so busy for the last month that I almost forgot about FreeBSD 12.0 which I had been looking forward to. Now it&#39;s just around the corner!
Although it&#39;s quite late, I tried to install 12.0-RC3 on a host behind a HTTP proxy and found that using a bootonly installer in this environment was a bit tricky. The following are the steps I took.
  Boot the host with a bootonly installer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>