<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>application on genneko</title>
    <link>https://genneko.github.io/tags/application/</link>
    <description>Recent content in application on genneko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2017 - 2020 genneko</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 17:06:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://genneko.github.io/tags/application/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Running X Applications on a Jail created with Bastille</title>
      <link>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/application/running-xapps-on-a-jail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 17:06:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/application/running-xapps-on-a-jail/</guid>
      <description>FreeBSD jails are often talked about from a security or system administration perspective.
Although it&amp;rsquo;s a perfectly valid point of view, jails can also be used for other purposes.
In fact, just recently I benefited from a jail in such a situation.
It once again convinced me that jails were really awesome and I&amp;rsquo;d like to write up this short article.
Assumptions  The host is a graphical desktop workstation running FreeBSD 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Joplin desktop app on FreeBSD</title>
      <link>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/application/howto-use-joplin-on-freebsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 20:26:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/application/howto-use-joplin-on-freebsd/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick note on how I build and use the latest Joplin desktop app on FreeBSD.
For my initial exploration of Joplin on FreeBSD, please refer to the previous post.
Target Version The current target version of this article is Joplin Electron release v1.0.187 (Mar 2020). Building Joplin I take the following steps to build Joplin desktop on my FreeBSD 12.1-RELEASE system (with XFCE4 desktop).
  Install dependencies such as Electron and Nodejs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Joplin (Terminal and Desktop) and Web Clipper on FreeBSD</title>
      <link>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/application/joplin-on-freebsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 23:20:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/application/joplin-on-freebsd/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR (2020-01-15)
This article describes my initial exploration of Joplin in June 2019. It&amp;rsquo;s not intended to be a tutorial/howto and it&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily up to date.
Please refer to the newer post for more up-to-date and concise description on how to use Joplin on FreeBSD.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Evernote since April 2011.
Although there were times the app got disappointing updates or the service was unexpectedly interrupted (or more often expectedly interrupted by regular maintenance), it had been a great app/service and hopefully it is and it will be.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>