<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wireguard on genneko</title>
    <link>https://genneko.github.io/tags/wireguard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in wireguard on genneko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2017 - 2020 genneko</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 22:46:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://genneko.github.io/tags/wireguard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a WireGuard Jail with the FreeBSD&#39;s Standard Tools</title>
      <link>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/networking/freebsd-wireguard-jail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 22:46:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/networking/freebsd-wireguard-jail/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I had an opportunity to build a WireGuard jail on a FreeBSD 12.1 host.
As it was really quick and easy to setup and it has been working completely fine for a month, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my experience with anyone interested in this topic.
 I would like to use WireGuard app on my Android phone to access my home NAS (a vanilla FreeBSD server) via the WireGuard tunnel and reach the Internet through the tunnel too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WireGuard on FreeBSD Quick Look Part 2: Android Remote Access</title>
      <link>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/networking/freebsd-wireguard-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 01:22:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/networking/freebsd-wireguard-android/</guid>
      <description>After playing briefly with WireGuard (See previous post) on FreeBSD VNET Jails, today I performed a quick test between a FreeBSD host and an Android device over the Internet.
NOTE: WireGuard is still in early stage of development. Android app is clearly marked with beta and Go-implementation (wireguard-go) has no official release yet. This article just shows you what I did to take a look at it.
2020-04-26: I wrote a new post on building a WireGuard jail with the FreeBSD&amp;rsquo;s standard tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WireGuard on FreeBSD Quick Look: Testing VPN in Jail Network</title>
      <link>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/networking/freebsd-wireguard-quicklook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 15:47:34 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://genneko.github.io/playing-with-bsd/networking/freebsd-wireguard-quicklook/</guid>
      <description>WireGuard is a new VPN application which focuses on simplicity thus security and speed. Although it was initially developed as a Linux kernel feature, now it has a userspace implementation in Go and binary packages are available for FreeBSD.
I used this weekend to have a quick look at it on FreeBSD 12.0.
This time I focused on site-to-site VPN setup. Maybe I will try remote-access VPN configuration in the near future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
